<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Manuu Connect</string>
    <string name="section_format">Hello World from section: %1$d</string>
    <string name="navigation_drawer_open">Open navigation drawer</string>
    <string name="navigation_drawer_close">Close navigation drawer</string>
    <string name="title_activity_contact">Map</string>
    <string name="contactUs">Address:
                             Weaker Section Colony,
                             Telecom Nagar, Gachibowli,
                             Hyderabad, Telangana 500032</string>
    <string name="title_activity_maps">Map</string>
    <string name="overview">Maulana Azad National Urdu University (MANUU) is a Central University established at National Level in 1998 by an act of Parliament to promote and develop the Urdu language and to impart vocational and technical Education in Urdu medium through conventional and distance modes. The Headquarters of the University is at an outstanding central location-Gachibowli, Hyderabad, sprawled over 200 acres. The students and staff of the University are drawn from throughout India. They are attracted by its commitment to excellence in quality Urdu education in all disciplines of knowledge.

The objectives of the University are as follows:

to promote and develop the Urdu language
to impart education and training in vocational and technical subjects through the medium of Urdu
to provide wider access to people desirous of pursuing programmes of higher education and training in Urdu medium through Campus and Distance modes and
to provide focus on women education.
The University’s campus education as on today boasts of seven Schools of Studies: namely,
1) School of Languages, Linguistics and Indology,
2) School of Commerce and Business Management,
3) School of Journalism and Mass Communication
4) School of Arts and Social Sciences
5) School of Sciences
6) School of Education and Training and
7)School of Computer Science Information Technology.
These seven Schools run 24 Departments, which in addition to offering masters programmes, provide research programmes at M. Phil. and Ph D level. These Schools have already churned out a considerable number of
M. Phil. Scholars. The focus of all these Schools is to search new areas of knowledge and to advance knowledge through research and application.

The University has established three Industrial Training Institutes (ITIs) and three Polytechnic Colleges in Hyderabad Bangalore and Dharbanga respectively. For all the disciplines on offer in ITI and Polytechnic, Urdu is the medium of instruction, which fulfils one of the objectives of the University of imparting technical subjects in Urdu. Additionally, the University established three Teacher Training Colleges at Srinagar, Darbhanga and Bhopal respectively, where personal and intellectual growth of teachers is realized through varied teacher training programmes.

True to its mission of widening the wings of Urdu and instilling a passion for Urdu among the new generation, the University has also established model schools that provide quality school education.

The University established a UGC-Academic Staff College in January 2007 in its campus with the sanction of UGC. The College offers Orientation and Refresher and Professional Development Programmes, and is engaged in various other academic activities. The University has a full-fledged ‘Instructional Media Centre (IMC), in its campus. IMC is engaged in production of curriculum based audio and video programmes to cater to the needs of students pursuing various academic programmes of MANUU in its Distance Education stream. Documentary programmes meant for the public at large are delivered through the broadcast mode. For this purpose, the University has entered into Memorandum of Understanding (MoU) with Doordarshan, Prasar Bharti, so that MANUU programmes are broadcast on the DD Urdu channel on a regular basis. The University’s Educational Programmes on Doordarshan’s Urdu Channel have been telecasted daily since 1st January 2010. The University has also established its first campus outside Hyderabad at Lucknow city from the academic year 2009-2010. The Lucknow Campus offers Post Graduate Programmes (M.A.) in Urdu, Arabic, Persian and English.
    </string>
<string name="history">Maulana Azad National Urdu University (MANUU) is a Central University established at National Level in 1998 by an act of Parliament to promote and develop the Urdu language and to impart vocational and technical education in Urdu medium through conventional and distance modes. The headquarters of the University is at an outstanding central location-Gachibowli, Hyderabad, sprawled over 200 acres. The students and staff of the University are drawn from throughout India. They are attracted by its commitment to excellence in quality Urdu education in all disciplines of knowledge.
</string>
    <string name="vcpage">Dear friends,

It is a feeling of joy to be with you. Maulana Azad National Urdu University, equipped with the mandate to quench the thirst of knowledge seekers through Urdu Medium, is a unique institution in real sense. MANUU has undergone massive changes in the recent years.

Now the University campus is dotted with new well designed buildings that are host to a large number of newly created departments, Centres and Civil Services Examination Coaching Academy. There are also new hostel buildings for the boys and girls besides a well equipped indoor stadium.

The way forward from here is to focus on reaching out to the unreached; to consolidate what has been built; to create good infrastructure at our off campuses; to improve the quality of education; to increase the knowledge base in Urdu and; to create conducive environment for quality research.
MANUU is a unique university which imparts education to its students through Urdu medium.  This characteristic of MANUU presents us with monumental challenges.

When MANUU began functioning in 1998 its primary route to offer education was through distance education mode. It remained so for the next few years and the number of students registered with the University swelled to about one lakh at one point of time. But somehow the attention to distance education mode got diluted.
MANUU has taken a decision recently to work on distance education mode seriously and clear all the hurdles in its way.

Right now there are thousands of students enlisted with the distance education mode, more than half of them being female. It has been decided to plug the lacuna in the system and tighten the monitoring mechanism at all the 160 Study Centres; nine Regional and five Sub-Regional Centres with the help of latest technology.  It has also been decided to open online admission system. The difficulties faced by students in counseling, writing examination and obtaining degrees, diplomas and certificates will be removed. All these and other measures are expected to increase the number of students in this system of education many-fold.

The other determination at MANUU is to reinforce self-confidence amongst students. They would be provided with facilities to become proficient in English with a view to enhancing their chances of employability. When they leave the campus, they should not feel inferior in any manner to job competitor from any other university or institution.

Another important dimension on which MANUU has begun to work is to increase the availability of knowledge material by producing and translating subject literature in Urdu.

    </string>
</resources>
